Henrique Colodetti Escanferla Farrell

Cellphone/WhatsApp: +55 31 9 9442 2707

hencolesc@gmail.com; https://www.linkedin.com/in/hencolesc

**Professional Summary** 

My name is Henrique Colodetti Escanferla Farrell and I was born in Vitória - ES and currently reside in Belo Horizonte -

MG. I completed my high school integrated with a technician in electrical engineering at the Federal Institute of Espírito

Santo. During this course I acquired theoretical and practical knowledge of installations, projects, engines, generators and

other electronic equipment in general. I completed my undergraduate degree with a Bachelor's Degree in Computer

Science at the Federal University of Paraná on the polytechnic campus in Curitiba. During this graduation, I learned all the

theory of computing, programming languages, analysis of algorithms, as well as specific subjects in the scientific areas of

the course that I was interested in. I find it very easy to learn other development tools and programming languages. I

always like to learn new things. I am organized and flexible to the needs of the moment, being able to adapt to critical

changes at work. I have resilience in working under pressure managing delivery deadlines. I want to develop in the IT

software and systems market and grow professionally, contributing to the company and its processes while enriching my

experience in the area.

Education

IFES - Federal Institute of Espírito Santo - Technician in Electrotechnics Integrated with High School - Finished in 12/2012

Technical course in electrotechnics with high school curriculum subjects

Knowledge in topics related to electrical engineering at a technical level such as generators, three-phase electric

motors, basic electronics, residential, building and industrial electrical projects

UFPR - Federal University of Paraná - Bachelor of Computer Science - Finished in 12/2017

Computer Tutorial Education Program - Member

Paraná Electric Power Company - Internship

### **Experiences**

# PET - Computer Tutorial Education Program - 04/2016 to 03/2017

- Worked in some academic and educational applications as a member of teaching, research and extension
  projects and activities. With emphasis, the web project A.D.E.G.A made in Python/Django which had the main
  objective of transforming academic data into graphs and other statistical information in order to support the course
  coordinator's decision making. See website at <a href="http://pet.inf.ufor.br/">http://pet.inf.ufor.br/</a>
- Tools used: Python/Django/SQlite/graphic libs in python/Git/Gitlab/Linux

## COPEL - Paraná Electric Power Company - 03/2017 to 11/2017

- Intern in the telecommunications sector developing applications and legacy web systems using
   Java/Hibernate/JSF with Primefaces and Omnifaces component packages
- Tools used: Java/JSF/Primefaces/Omnifaces/Oracle SQL/Eclipse/Git/Gitlab/Jira/Windows

### APSIS Informatics - 03/2018 to 10/2019

- Analyst developer of web systems as a solution for healthcare applications. The migration of a legacy system from Java/Jboss/SOAP/JSF/Richfaces to Java/Jboss/JSON/Vue.js using the ElementUI component package, whose main objective was to manage data on beneficiaries of the collective health insurance offered by customers of this system complying with an extended regulation of the national health agency of Brazil
- Tools used:
   Java/Eclipse/JAX-WS/REST/EJB/JasperReports/Hibernate/PostgreSql/PgAdmin/Vue.js/ElementUI/CSS/HTML/
   JavaScript/Visual Studio/Mercurial/Git/Gradle/Yarn/Redmine/Linux

# Reply do Brasil Informatics Systems - Allocated at Fiat FCA Betim - Partially remote - 10/2019 to 11/2020

- Analyst developer of backend systems integrations using SOAP, REST, FTP, GCP, AWS, Message Queue,
   Connect Direct, IBM API Connect, IBM Integration Bus technologies, among others depending on the need of the context so that the systems integration works as expected
- During development, it was necessary to analyze and provide specific solutions using internal nuances in the
  operation of the previously mentioned proprietary IBM tools IBM API Connect and IBM Integration Bus. With an
  emphasis on javascript components using IBM API Connect, where each request goes in and out of a
  SOAP/REST integration using this tool produces a log with the same object format as the other integration's logs

using other tools and then sends it via REST API to the GCP in a log table so that it can be analyzed later. With this, it became easy to send context data from each API, each request and each response, whether this is a success or not, without the need for additional code development, becoming a kind of library that was used by all the integrations developed with this tool in question.

- Worked on a separate project created from scratch with the aim of automating testing of all SOAP / REST web integrations using test collections in Postman / Newman and Gitlab CI / CD. This way, with each confirmation or with the touch of a button, all tests are executed using the image of the dockers and also with kubernetes. The results are collected and presented in an html report that can be opened with any browser, facilitating visualization and troubleshooting in development / approval / production environments
- Tools used: Java/Javascript/VisualStudio/Eclipse/IBM API Connect/IBM Integration Bus/IBM WebSphere
- Message Queue/IBM Sterling Connect:Direct/SQL Server/SoapUI/Postman/Newman/Git/Gitlab/Jira/Google Cloud
   Platform/Google Cloud SQL/AWS/Swagger/Microservices/DDD/Docker/Kubernetes

### DOMVS IT - Allocated at BTG Pactual | Remote - 05/2021 until now

- Developer analyst of Java/Kotlin Spring web systems for BTG Pactual including backend projects for the BTG+ digital bank application
- Among other developments, I worked on accounting for the use of benefits from the new BLACK banking services
  plan, including the benefits of reduced exchange rates and use of the VIP lounge key at airports in Brazil and
  around the world, sending amounts for cashback or chargeback when cancellations of transactions occur.
- Tools used: Java/Kotlin/Spring Boot/PostgreSQL/DynamoDB/SQS/Kinesis/Kafka/AWS/IntelliJ
   IDE/Jenkins/Jira/Kibana/Datadog/API/RESTful/Swagger/Microservices/DDD/Docker/Kubernetes

#### Languages

- Portuguese Fluent
- English Speaking/Listening/Reading/Writing: Advanced/Advanced/Advanced/Advanced

#### **Observations**

I'm an experienced developer who can learn anything related with IT delivering solutions taking into account the customer's needs. If I don't know some tool, language, or don't have enough experience with it, I will strive to be the candidate that meets the expectations of this opportunity.

# **Additional links**

Portfolio of works during graduation at UFPR: <a href="https://github.com/hencolesc">https://github.com/hencolesc</a>

My course conclusion work, in PDF: <a href="http://docdro.id/FdkNn3d">http://docdro.id/FdkNn3d</a>